<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <Objectives>To assess the efficacy and safety of GnRH analogues given before or in parallel to chemotherapy to prevent chemotherapy‐related ovarian damage in premenopausal women with malignant or non‐malignant conditions.</Objectives>
<TypesofStudies>Randomised controlled trials (RCTs) in all languages that examined the effect of GnRH analogues for chemotherapy‐induced ovarian failure in premenopausal women were eligible for inclusion in the review. We included studies published in abstract form, if extraction of data was possible, and treated these as being at high risk of bias, if insufficient information was available. Where data extraction was not possible, we included studies as awaiting classification.</TypesofStudies>
<TypesofParticipants>Inclusion criteria Premenopausal women (confirmed by age, menstrual history, ovarian sonography and/or hormone levels, such as FSH and estradiol) with malignant or non‐malignant conditions, receiving GnRH analogues supplementation before or in parallel to chemotherapy. Exclusion criteria Premenopausal women who had taken oral contraceptive pills or hormone replacement therapy after chemotherapy.</TypesofParticipants>
<TypesofInterventions>GnRH agonists or antagonists or both versus placebo or other interventions, before or in parallel to chemotherapy Combination of GnRH agonists and antagonists versus GnRH agonists or antagonists alone, before or in parallel to chemotherapy GnRH agonists or antagonists or both plus other interventions versus GnRH agonists or antagonists or both, or other methods alone, before or in parallel to chemotherapy (where 'other interventions' indicate alternatives to GnRH analogues to preserve ovarian function, such as oral contraceptive pills or cryopreservation of embryo etc., and are the same in each arm of the RCT comparison)</TypesofInterventions>
<TypesofOutcomeMeasures>Primary outcomes Menstruation recovery or maintenance: maintenance or recovery of menstruation (normal or oligomenorrhoea) with or without clear evidence of ovulation Premature ovarian failure: no resumption of menstrual activity with postmenopausal FSH levels at least one year after the end of chemotherapy Pregnancy Secondary outcomes Ovulation (confirmed by, for example, ovarian sonography or serum progesterone levels) Ovarian sonography (antral follicle count, size of ovary, etc.) Hormone levels (FSH, LH, AMH, inhibin, estradiol, progesterone, etc.) Anti‐cancer efficacy (five‐year survival rate, etc.) Adverse effects (symptoms of hypoestrogenaemia, such as hot flashes, headaches and osteoporosis, etc.)</TypesofOutcomeMeasures>
</root>

