<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <Objectives>To investigate ocular and systemic effects of, and quality of life associated with, intravitreous injection of anti‐VEGF agents (pegaptanib, ranibizumab, and bevacizumab) versus no anti‐VEGF treatment for patients with neovascular AMD To compare the relative effects of one of these anti‐VEGF agents versus another when administered in comparable dosages and regimens</Objectives>
<TypesofStudies>We included only RCTs in this review.</TypesofStudies>
<TypesofParticipants>We included trials in which participants had neovascular AMD as defined by study investigators.</TypesofParticipants>
<TypesofInterventions>We included studies that compared anti‐VEGF treatment versus another treatment, sham treatment, or no treatment. We did not include studies that compared different doses of one anti‐VEGF treatment against another, studies that included no control or comparator group, or studies that used anti‐VEGF agents in combination with other treatments. We did not include studies of aflibercept (VEGF Trap‐Eye/EYLEA solution) or studies that compared different treatment schedules (e.g. monthly vs as needed dosing), because other Cochrane reviews have evaluated these interventions (Li 2016; Sarwar 2016).</TypesofInterventions>
<TypesofOutcomeMeasures>Primary outcomes The primary outcome for this review was based on best‐corrected visual acuity (BCVA) at one‐year follow‐up. All included RCTs randomized only one eye per participant (i.e. the study eye); therefore we defined the primary outcome for the comparison of treatments as the proportion of participants who gained 15 or more letters (three lines) of BCVA in the study eye when BCVA was measured on a visual acuity chart with a LogMAR scale. Secondary outcomes Visual acuity outcomes Proportion of participants who gained 15 or more letters of BCVA in the study eye as measured at two‐year follow‐up Proportion of participants who lost fewer than 15 letters of visual acuity at one year and at two years Proportion of participants who lost fewer than 30 letters of visual acuity at one year and at two years Proportion of participants for whom blindness was avoided in the study eye, defined as eyes with visual acuity better than 20/200 at one year and at two years Proportion of participants maintaining visual acuity, defined as a gain of zero or more letters (i.e. no loss of BCVA from baseline) at one year and at two years Mean change in visual acuity from baseline to one year and to two years Other secondary outcomes Contrast sensitivity, reading speed, or any other validated measure of visual function as measured in the included studies Assessment of morphologic characteristics by fluorescein angiography or OCT, including mean change in size of CNV, mean change in size of total lesion, and mean change in central retinal thickness (CRT) Quality of life measures, as assessed with any validated measurement scale Economic data, such as comparative cost analyses Ocular or systemic adverse outcomes Follow‐up We included only trials in which participants were followed for at least one year. We also included outcomes at two‐year follow‐up when these data were available.</TypesofOutcomeMeasures>
</root>

