<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <Objectives>To determine and compare the effects of toothpastes of different fluoride concentrations (parts per million (ppm)) in preventing dental caries in children, adolescents, and adults.</Objectives>
<TypesofStudies>Parallel‐group randomised controlled trials (RCTs) (individually or cluster‐randomised), which compared toothbrushing with fluoride toothpaste with toothbrushing with a non‐fluoride toothpaste or toothpaste of a different fluoride concentration, with a follow‐up period of at least 1 year. We excluded studies where random allocation was not used or indicated. Due to the high possibility of contamination of one part of the mouth from another, it would not be appropriate to use a split‐mouth design to evaluate the effects of this intervention, and so we excluded any studies with this design.</TypesofStudies>
<TypesofParticipants>Children, adolescents or adults, irrespective of the initial level of dental caries, background exposure to fluoride, receipt of dental treatment, nationality, setting where the intervention was received or age at recruitment to the trial. We excluded studies where the participants were selected on the basis of special (general or oral) health conditions.</TypesofParticipants>
<TypesofInterventions>We included studies comparing toothbrushing with a fluoride toothpaste with toothbrushing with another fluoride toothpaste of a different concentration or with a non‐fluoride toothpaste or no toothpaste. On the basis of fluoride concentrations of toothpastes in regular use, we proposed the following categories: 0 (parts per million (ppm)) fluoride (F) (non‐fluoride or placebo toothpaste) 250 ppm F 440 to 550 ppm F 1000 to 1250 ppm F 1450 to 1500 ppm F 1700 to 2200 ppm F 2400 to 2800 ppm F. There were no restrictions placed on the fluoride agents which could be used singly or in combination: sodium fluoride (NaF) sodium monofluorophosphate (SMFP) stannous fluoride (SnF2) acidulated phosphate fluoride (APF) amine fluoride (AmF). Toothpastes could be formulated with any compatible abrasive system. These included dicalcium phosphate, sodium metaphosphate, calcium carbonate, silica, zirconium silicate, or calcium pyrophosphate. There was no restriction on fluoride concentration (ppm), amount or duration of application, frequency of use, toothbrushing technique (including supervised toothbrushing), or post‐toothbrushing procedure. We excluded studies where the intervention group or both the intervention and control groups received any additional active agent or caries preventive measure (e.g. chlorhexidine agent, fluoride varnish application, fluoride mouthrinse) as part of the study in addition to the fluoride or placebo toothpaste. Studies where the intervention group alone received any additional potentially active agent in the toothpaste such as xylitol, triclosan, N‐lauroyl sarcosinate, and casein phosphopeptide‐amorphous calcium phosphate (CPP–ACP) were excluded; studies where both the intervention group and comparator group received any additional potentially active agent in the toothpaste were included. This protocol change was instigated to reflect the change in toothpaste formulation since the initial review. Many types of toothpaste now combine the caries preventive benefit of fluoride with other therapeutic agents to control plaque (antibacterial agents), tartar, and gum disease. Studies where both the intervention and control groups included participants receiving additional measures as part of their routine oral care such as supervised brushing, fissure sealants, were included, as were studies that were undertaken in areas with fluoridation of the community water supply.</TypesofInterventions>
<TypesofOutcomeMeasures>Primary outcomes Caries increment as measured by: change from baseline in the decayed, (missing), and filled surface or teeth index (D(M)FS/T), in all permanent teeth erupted at the start and erupting over the course of the study (dental caries is defined here as being clinically and radiologically recorded at the dentine level of diagnosis); change from baseline in the decayed, (missing/extraction indicated), and filled surface or teeth index (d(e/m)fs/t) in all primary teeth; change in the proportion of participants developing new caries. Where possible we extracted data on D(M)FS/T, d(e/m)fs/t, and the proportion of participants developing new caries. We acknowledged that the primary outcome of caries could be measured and reported in a number of different ways. To account for this, the choice of outcome followed an adapted version of the hierarchy presented in the earlier review (Walsh 2010): DFS/T data would be chosen over DMFS/T data, and these would be chosen over DS/T or FS/T data for 'all surface types combined' would be chosen over data for 'specific types' only data for 'all erupted and erupting teeth combined' (E + U) would be chosen over data for 'erupted' (E) only, and these over data for 'erupting' (U) only data for dentinal/cavitated caries lesions (D3 level) would be chosen over data for enamel/non‐cavitated lesions (D1 level) net caries increment data would be chosen over crude (observed) increment data data from 'clinical and radiological examinations combined' would be chosen over data from 'clinical' (cl) only, and these over 'radiological' (xr) only. We defined clinical examinations as an examination using visual or tactile methods or both (VT) using a conventional lighting source. We excluded studies reporting caries using a non‐clinical examination alone (e.g. electronic caries monitor, quantitative light‐induced fluorescence) follow‐up nearest to 3 years (often the one at the end of the study period) would be chosen over all follow‐up. Clinical and radiographic examinations provided the definition of different stages or grades of caries lesions. These have been grouped into two basic grades for each method of examination. Clinical: non‐cavitated incipient enamel lesions clinically visible as white spots or discoloured fissures (NCA); lesions showing loss of enamel continuity that can be recorded clinically (undermined enamel, softened floor, walls) or showing frank cavitation (CA). Radiographic: any radiolucency in enamel/enamel‐dentine junction (ER); radiolucency into dentine (DR). Secondary outcomes Adverse effects such as irritation, dental staining/discolouration, etc.</TypesofOutcomeMeasures>
</root>

