<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <Objectives>available in English Español To determine the impact of perioperative epidural analgesia in adults undergoing cardiac surgery, with or without cardiopulmonary bypass, on perioperative mortality and cardiac, pulmonary, or neurological morbidity.</Objectives>
<TypesofStudies>We included randomized controlled trials (RCTs). We excluded observational studies, quasi‐randomized trials, cross‐over trials, and cluster‐randomized trials. We did not exclude studies on the basis of language of publication or publication status.</TypesofStudies>
<TypesofParticipants>We included adult participants undergoing general anaesthesia for all types of cardiac surgery with or without cardiopulmonary bypass.</TypesofParticipants>
<TypesofInterventions>We included trials that compared cardiac surgery including one group of participants with and one group of participants without epidural analgesia ( Table 1). We excluded studies that compared cardiac surgery with participants with and participants without spinal anaesthesia. We included studies in which investigators administered epidural analgesia as a single shot block or as a continuous infusion for any duration and containing a local anaesthetic alone (extended duration or not), or in combination with an opioid (extended duration or not), or an opioid alone. We did not exclude studies in which trialists added an adjuvant other than an opioid to the solution. We excluded trials comparing nerve blocks versus systemic analgesia. For the comparator, we included all other modes of analgesia and divided them into: all forms of systemic analgesia (opioid‐based regimen or other), regardless of the route of administration (intravenous (with or without a self‐administered patient‐controlled device), intramuscular, or oral analgesia); peripheral nerve blocks; intrapleural analgesia; and wound infiltration. </TypesofInterventions>
<TypesofOutcomeMeasures>Primary outcomes Risk of mortality (0 to 30 days, six months, and one year) Secondary outcomes Risk of myocardial infarction (0 to 30 days; study author's definitions ( Table 2))Risk of pulmonary complications Riisk of atrial fibrillation or atrial flutter during surgery and up to two weeks after surgery Risk of neurological complications Duration of tracheal intubation ( Table 5) Pain scores (rest and movement at 6 to 8, 24, 48, and 72 hours) Haemodynamic support (in hospital)</TypesofOutcomeMeasures>
</root> 

