<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <Objectives>To assess the relative effectiveness (i.e. reduction of pain) and safety of cyclodestructive procedures (i.e. CPC and ECP) compared with other procedures (i.e. aqueous shunts) in people with refractory glaucoma of any type and to assess the relative effectiveness and safety of individual cyclodestructive procedures compared with each other.</Objectives>
<TypesofStudies>We included only randomized controlled trials (RCTs) and quasi‐RCTs (e.g., studies where the method of allocation is not considered strictly random such as by alternation, date of birth, or medical record number).</TypesofStudies>
<TypesofParticipants>We included RCTs in which participants underwent a secondary procedure for refractory glaucoma (medically uncontrolled glaucoma for which other surgeries have failed). We included all types of glaucoma (i.e. primary open‐angle glaucoma (OAG), angle‐closure glaucoma (ACG), and secondary glaucoma such as neovascular, pigmentary, and exfoliation glaucoma). There were no restrictions based on participant age, gender, ethnicity, or comorbidity.</TypesofParticipants>
<TypesofInterventions>We included all trials that compared cyclodestruction with aqueous shunts or another cyclodestructive procedure (CPC or ECP). We included trials with all types of lasers (i.e. ruby, Nd:YAG, diode), routes of administration (non‐contact, contact), and laser settings. The primary comparison of interest was any cyclodestructive procedure versus another glaucoma treatment (aqueous shunts); the secondary comparisons were individual cyclodestructive procedures versus another cyclodestructive procedure.</TypesofInterventions>
<TypesofOutcomeMeasures>Primary outcomes Change from baseline in pain severity as reported by the participant or change in number of pain medications prescribed from baseline to 12 months postintervention. Secondary outcomes Mean change in intraocular pressure (IOP) from baseline (immediate preoperative IOP) in study eyes at one week, one month, three months, six months, 12 months, and last follow‐up after the procedure, measured using Goldmann tonometry, Tono‐Pen, or another standard device. If sufficient information was available from the included studies, we planned to examine IOP in time‐to‐event analysis. When mean change in IOP from baseline was not reported, we used the mean IOP values at a time point to estimate the between‐group treatment effects. Mean change in best‐corrected visual acuity in study eyes at 12 months postintervention, measured by logarithm of the minimum angle of resolution (logMAR) chart or equivalent. Mean change in mean deviation in study eyes from baseline at 12 months postintervention as measured by automated perimetry. Mean number of prescribed glaucoma medications, both topical and systemic, at 12 months postintervention. Proportion of study eyes requiring additional glaucoma surgery by 12 months postintervention. Adverse outcomes We documented adverse outcomes reported by the included studies (i.e. prolonged inflammation, hypotony, phthisis, fibrin exudates). Since cyclodestructive surgeries are intraocular procedures, we also documented reports of endophthalmitis, retinal detachment, and choroidal hemorrhage. Quality of life data We planned to describe and compare quality of life outcomes by procedure if available.</TypesofOutcomeMeasures>
</root>

