<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <Objectives>available in English Español To assess the effectiveness of psychological therapies for the treatment of depression in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD).</Objectives>
<TypesofStudies>All the studies included in this review are randomised controlled trials (RCTs); with one study being a cluster RCT. We had intended to include cross‐over trials if identified by the search; however, we did not find any.</TypesofStudies>
<TypesofParticipants>Participant characteristics We included studies involving adults, 40 years of age and older, of either gender, and of any ethnicity. As most people with COPD begin experiencing COPD symptoms in their 40s, it is unlikely that individuals under 40 years of age would be diagnosed with clinically significant COPD (WHO 2018). Diagnosis As per protocol, studies were eligible to be included in this review if the participants were diagnosed with COPD (FEV1/FVC less than 70% predicted) and a recognised depressive disorder (or depressive symptoms) at the time of recruitment to the trial – assessed using standardised diagnostic criteria, or a formal, validated instrument (i.e. a questionnaire), or both. Considering that trials testing effectiveness of psychological therapies often apply diagnostic criteria for depression after randomisation and at baseline assessment (i.e. participants are not included in the trial on the basis of having a depressive diagnosis or depression symptoms), we allowed inclusion of these studies as well. The COPD diagnosis must have been made by a medical professional, clinically, or by the Global Initiative for Chronic Obstructive Lung Disease criteria, or both (WHO 2018). Depression diagnostic criteria included, but were not limited to, DSM‐3, DSM‐4 (APA 2000), DSM‐5 (APA 2013). Comorbidities As long as a comorbidity was not the primary focus, we included studies with participants with comorbid chronic physical conditions (e.g. hypertension, cardiovascular disease, metabolic disease, asthma), comorbid mental disorders (e.g. anxiety), or both. For example, we did not include interventions where anxiety was the primary focus. Setting All types of settings were eligible for inclusion, e.g. inpatient (psychiatric setting, inpatient treatment for COPD), outpatient, and primary care. Subset data As per protocol, studies containing subsets of eligible participants were permitted, providing 60% of the study population had clinically diagnosed COPD and a depressive disorder. However, participants with clinically diagnosed COPD and a depressive disorder were the primary population in all of the studies included in this review.</TypesofParticipants>
<TypesofInterventions>Comorbidities As long as a comorbidity was not the primary focus, we included studies with participants with comorbid chronic physical conditions (e.g. hypertension, cardiovascular disease, metabolic disease, asthma), comorbid mental disorders (e.g. anxiety), or both. For example, we did not include interventions where anxiety was the primary focus.</TypesofInterventions>
<TypesofOutcomeMeasures>Setting All types of settings were eligible for inclusion, e.g. inpatient (psychiatric setting, inpatient treatment for COPD), outpatient, and primary care.</TypesofOutcomeMeasures>
</root>

