<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <Objectives>To assess the effects of physical exercise training on functional performance in people with spinal muscular atrophy type 3, and to identify any adverse effects.</Objectives>
<TypesofStudies>We included randomized controlled trials (RCTs) and quasi‐RCTs. Quasi‐RCTs are studies that use a quasi‐random method to allocate participants to groups, such as alternation, date of birth, or case record number (Higgins 2011). In the 'Discussion' section, we described relevant cross‐over studies, case control studies and multi‐ and single‐case reports that fulfilled the same standards as eligible RCTs regarding diagnostic criteria, description of intervention, and outcome measures. We considered trials available in any language, whether available as full‐text articles, abstracts, or unpublished data only.</TypesofStudies>
<TypesofParticipants>We included studies in children from the age of five years and adults with a diagnosis of spinal muscular atrophy (SMA) type 3 (Kugelberg‐Welander syndrome) who fulfilled the clinical criteria and had a deletion or mutation of the survival motor neuron 1 (SMN1) gene (5q11.2‐13.2) confirmed by genetic analysis (Lefebvre 1995). Studies of mixed populations, e.g. studies that include mixed neuromuscular diseases or mixed SMA types, were only eligible for inclusion in the review if they reported results for SMA type 3 separately.</TypesofParticipants>
<TypesofInterventions>We included trials that used any form of physical exercise training of skeletal muscles, including aerobic exercise and strength training, carried out for a period of at least 12 weeks, compared with placebo, standard or usual care, or another type of non‐physical intervention. We included trials that provided co‐interventions to each group equally. We excluded studies of respiratory muscle training or that used a non‐exercised limb as a control. We included trials that used training programs standardized on frequency, intensity, time, and type of training, with an incremental exercise protocol.</TypesofInterventions>
<TypesofOutcomeMeasures>We included studies that reported outcomes at baseline and at the end of training. We would have reported longer‐term outcomes if they had been available. Primary outcomes Walking distance on the six‐minute walk test (6MWT; Dunaway 2016; Montes 2010). Functional performance, measured with the Hammersmith Functional Motor Scale ‐ Expanded (HFMSE; O'Hagen 2007), Motor Function Measure (MFM; Vuillerot 2013), and timed tests (10‐meter walk/run test (10MWT), Gower's time, or Timed Up and Go Test (TUG; Dunaway 2014)). Secondary outcomes Cardiopulmonary exercise capacity, assessed with validated cycle ergometry (W, mL/kg/min) or treadmill testing (mL/min, time to limitation) (Bartels 2015). Muscle strength, including maximal isometric and isokinetic voluntary contraction, measured with validated dynamometry (Newton/N*M) and validated Manual Muscle Testing (MMT; an ordinal scale). Fatigue, assessed in adults with the Fatigue Severity Scale (FSS; Werlauff 2014) and in children with the Pediatric Quality of Life Inventory Multi Dimensional Fatigue Score (PedsQLMFS; Varni 2004). Physical activity, assessed with questionnaires or accelerometry. Quality of life, assessed in adults with the 36‐Item Short‐Form Health Survey (SF‐36; Kruitwagen‐Van Reenen 2016) questionnaire and in children with the Pediatric Quality of Life Inventory Neuromuscular Module (PedsQLNM; Iannaccone 2009). Serious adverse events leading to withdrawal, such as debilitating fatigue, medical treatment, and hospitalization. We reported continuous outcomes as changes from baseline.</TypesofOutcomeMeasures>
</root>

