<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <Objectives>To determine whether ultrasound guidance offers any clinical advantage when neuraxial and peripheral nerve blocks are performed in children in terms of decreasing failure rate or the rate of complications.</Objectives>
<TypesofStudies>We included all parallel randomized controlled trials that evaluated the effect of ultrasound guidance when a regional blockade technique was performed in children and that included any of our selected outcomes. We excluded observational studies, quasi‐randomized trials, cross‐over trials, and cluster‐randomized trials. We did not exclude studies based on language of publication or publication status.</TypesofStudies>
<TypesofParticipants>We included studies performed in children (≤ 18 years of age) undergoing any type of surgical procedure (open or laparoscopic) for which a neuraxial (spinal, epidural, caudal, or combined spinal and epidural) or peripheral nerve block (any peripheral nerve block including fascial (fascia iliaca, transversus abdominis plane, rectus sheath blocks) or perivascular blocks), for surgical anaesthesia (alone or in combination with general anaesthesia) or for postoperative analgesia, was performed with ultrasound guidance. We excluded studies in which regional blockade was used to treat chronic pain.</TypesofParticipants>
<TypesofInterventions>We included studies in which ultrasound guidance was used to perform the technique in real time (in‐plane or out‐of‐plane), as pre‐scanning before the procedure, or to evaluate the spread of the local anaesthetic so the position of the needle could be adjusted or the block complemented. For control groups, we accepted any other technique used to perform the block including landmarks, loss of resistance (air or fluid), click, paraesthesia, nerve stimulator or transarterial. Infiltration of local anaesthetics was accepted. We excluded no studies based on the specific technique used as the comparator.</TypesofInterventions>
<TypesofOutcomeMeasures>We evaluated differences between treatment and control groups based on the following outcomes. Primary outcomes Success rate (study author's definition). Pain scores at one hour after surgery (any ascendent or descendent pain scale used by study authors). Block duration (study author's definition; 0 to 1 day). Secondary outcomes Time to perform the block (minutes if available). Number of needle passes. Minor complications: bloody puncture, transient neurological injury, seizure from systemic local anaesthetic toxicity, block infections without neurological injury. Major complications: cardiac arrest from local anaesthetic toxicity, lasting neurological injury (lasting more than three months).</TypesofOutcomeMeasures>
</root>

