<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <Objectives>available in English Español To assess the effects of yoga for treating urinary incontinence in women.</Objectives>
<TypesofStudies>We included randomised controlled trials (RCTs) and the first period of cross‐over RCTs. We excluded quasi‐randomised controlled trials (i.e. trials in which assignment to treatment was made using a non‐random method such as alternation) because the method of allocation may lead to biased estimates of effect. We did not restrict study eligibility by language or publication status. We only included health economic studies conducted alongside studies that were included in the clinical component of this systematic review (Shemilt 2011).</TypesofStudies>
<TypesofParticipants>We included studies with women aged 18 years or more who were diagnosed as having urinary incontinence on the basis of symptoms, signs or urodynamic evaluation (as defined by the trial authors). We only included trials that recruited both men and women if at least 90% of participants were women or if the trial provided demographic and outcome data separately for women. We included trials with women diagnosed as having stress, urgency or mixed urinary incontinence, as well as trials with participants who had mixed or unclassified types of urinary incontinence. We included trials carried out on women who were experiencing urinary incontinence during the antenatal or postnatal period. Because this group has physiological differences from women who are not pregnant or postpartum, and the natural history of incontinence in this population differs from that in non‐pregnant women, the observed effects of the intervention may differ in this group. We therefore did not group this population with women who were not pregnant or postpartum and we planned to analyse the studies separately throughout the review. We excluded studies of women who had urinary incontinence thought to be due to factors beyond the urinary tract such as neurological or psychiatric disorders, cognitive impairment, or mobility problems. We also excluded studies that focused on women who were experiencing nocturnal enuresis.</TypesofParticipants>
<TypesofInterventions>We included studies of yoga as a treatment for urinary incontinence, where the study report specified that the intervention was 'yoga' provided at any dose, with any frequency and for any duration, because we believe these factors are likely to vary in practice. We included interventions that belonged to any yoga tradition but excluded studies in which the yoga intervention did not include a physical practice component. We included studies that compared yoga to no treatment or to another active treatment. We also included studies that compared yoga as an adjunct to other treatments versus those same treatments without yoga. The types of included comparisons were as follows. Yoga versus no specific active intervention (e.g. usual care, waiting list). Yoga versus an active intervention (e.g. lifestyle intervention or pelvic floor muscle training), for which we considered different active comparators separately (e.g. yoga versus lifestyle advice, yoga versus pelvic floor muscle training). Yoga plus an intervention versus the same intervention without yoga (e.g. yoga as an add‐on intervention to pelvic floor training versus pelvic floor training alone), for which we considered different interventions separately. We included studies in which co‐interventions were provided if they were similar between intervention groups (e.g. both the yoga and the comparison groups received advice on behavioural management techniques). Studies that compare yoga to a sham yoga intervention do not appear to be common (Park 2014). However, we planned that we would consider such studies to represent an additional type of comparison (i.e. yoga versus sham yoga) and would analyse them separately. We excluded studies of interventions based on yoga (e.g. exercises based on yoga postures) but not characterised as yoga, as well as studies of multimodal interventions in which yoga is only one component amongst others, such as mindfulness‐based stress reduction (MBSR).</TypesofInterventions>
<TypesofOutcomeMeasures>We used outcomes suggested by the Standardisation Committee of the International Continence Society (Bø 2017; Haylen 2010). The following five categories of outcomes are recommended for research investigating the effect of therapeutic interventions for women with urinary incontinence (Lose 2001): The woman’s observations (e.g. symptoms); Quantification of the woman's symptoms (e.g. urine loss); The clinician’s observations (anatomical and functional signs); The woman's quality of life (urinary incontinence ‐ specific and general); Economic measures. In this review, we considered at least one outcome from each of the first four categories. We included specific outcomes that are commonly found in other Cochrane Incontinence reviews for urinary incontinence in women so that this review may produce results that are easily compared to or combined with those of other reviews of treatment for the same condition. Primary outcomes Number of women who report they are cured (they no longer experience urinary incontinence). Number of women who report cure or improvement of urinary incontinence. Urinary incontinence condition‐ or symptom‐specific quality of life, as measured by any relevant scale (e.g. the Urinary Incontinence Quality of Life scale (Patrick 1999), the Incontinence Impact Questionnaire (Uebersax 1995), the International Consultation on Incontinence Modular Questionnaire Lower Urinary Tract Symptoms Quality of Life (ICIQ‐LUTSqol) (Nystrom 2015), or the Pelvic Floor Distress Inventory (PFDI) and the Pelvic Floor Impact Questionnaire (PFIQ) (Barber 2001)). Secondary outcomes Quantification of symptoms Number of micturitions (daily). Number of episodes of incontinence (daily). Urine loss as measured with a pad or paper towel weight test (either the short‐ or long‐term test). Symptoms as reported by study participants on any condition‐specific scale (e.g. the Severity Index for Urinary Incontinence in Women (Sandvik 1993)). Clinician's observations (anatomical and functional signs) Clinical assessment of presence of incontinence, such as urine leakage during a cough test. Measurement of pelvic floor muscle function, such as by electromyography, vaginal squeeze pressure, pelvic floor muscle force, and morphological measurements (dynamometry, ultrasound). Quality of life Quality of life measured on a scale that is not condition‐ or symptom‐specific (e.g. the 36‐Item Short Form Health Survey (SF‐36)). Depression, anxiety or distress as measured on relevant scales (e.g. Beck Depression Inventory (BDI), Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS)). Other measures of emotional and social impact of the disorder such as the bothersomeness of the condition, the social impact of the condition and sexual functioning. Adverse effects Number of adverse effects (e.g. pain, discomfort). Main outcomes for 'Summary of findings' tables The GRADE working group recommends including up to seven critical outcomes in a systematic review (Guyatt 2011a; Guyatt 2011b). We therefore considered the following outcomes for assessing the certainty of the evidence: Number of women who report they are cured (they no longer experience urinary incontinence); Number of women who report cure or improvement of urinary incontinence; Urinary incontinence condition‐specific or symptom‐specific quality of life; Number of micturitions (daily); Number of episodes of incontinence (daily); Adverse effects. Timing of outcome assessment We grouped all outcomes into three time points: short‐term (closest to three months after randomisation), intermediate‐term (closest to six months after randomisation) and long‐term (closest to one year after randomisation). When an included trial presented multiple time points, we considered the short‐term time point as primary and other time points as secondary.</TypesofOutcomeMeasures>
</root>

