<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <Objectives>To assess the effects of interventions for infantile seborrhoeic dermatitis in children from birth to 24 months of age.</Objectives>
<TypesofStudies>We included randomised controlled trials (RCTs) of interventions for ISD.</TypesofStudies>
<TypesofParticipants>We included children from birth to 24 months diagnosed with ISD or cradle cap, based on clinical diagnosis by a healthcare practitioner. Where a study included a small minority of participants older than 24 months, we attempted to contact the authors to obtain data for the group under 24 months of age, and if unable to obtain this, we included the study on the basis that a small number of older participants would not influence the overall results.</TypesofParticipants>
<TypesofInterventions>All interventions were included, whether behavioural or pharmacological (including complementary and alternative medicines). We compared the following: any treatment versus no treatment or placebo; or two or more treatments or combinations of treatments. We grouped analyses where possible into types of treatment.</TypesofInterventions>
<TypesofOutcomeMeasures>We included trials in the review even if they do not report relevant outcomes, but we did not plan to include these trials in a meta‐analysis. We would have provided reasons for exclusion from analysis had a meta‐analysis been done. Primary outcomes Change in severity score from baseline to end of study (described by measures of surface area, redness, crust, or scale) (continuous outcome). Percentage of infants who developed adverse effects or intolerance to treatment (dichotomous outcome). Secondary outcomes Improvement in quality of life (QoL) as reported by parents: either continuous (score on QoL scale) or dichotomous (improved or not). The included studies used different scales of severity or QoL, such that we were we unable to standardise these scales (so that they could be combined in a meta‐analysis), and instead describe the outcomes narratively.</TypesofOutcomeMeasures>
</root>

