<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <Objectives>To assess the effects of single‐inhaler LABA/LAMA combinations versus placebo on clinically meaningful outcomes in patients with stable COPD.</Objectives>
<TypesofStudies>We included parallel‐group and cross‐over randomised controlled trials (RCTs). We included studies reported as full‐text, those published as abstract only, and unpublished data. We excluded very short‐term trials (i.e. ≤ three weeks in duration).</TypesofStudies>
<TypesofParticipants>We included adults (≥ 40 years old) with a diagnosis of stable COPD. We recorded study authors' definition of stable COPD. We did not exclude participants with comorbidities.</TypesofParticipants>
<TypesofInterventions>We included trials comparing once‐daily LABA/LAMA in a single inhaler (i.e. fixed dose combination) versus placebo. We included studies that allowed participants to continue using their ICS during the trial as long as the ICS was not part of the randomised treatment; if ICS was administered in combination with LABA prior to the trial, participants should be transitioned to the equivalent ICS monotherapy prior to study start. The effect of continued ICS use was planned to be examined by subgroup analysis (see Subgroup analysis and investigation of heterogeneity).</TypesofInterventions>
<TypesofOutcomeMeasures>Primary outcomes All‐cause mortality. Serious Adverse Events (SAE) of any cause. Acute Exacerbations of COPD (AECOPD). Respiratory Health‐related Quality of Life (HRQoL), as measured by the St. George’s Respiratory Questionnaire (SGRQ). Chronic Respiratory Questionnaire (CRQ). Comments about primary outcomes Serious adverse events SAEs can include death, life‐threatening adverse reaction, hospitalisation or increased length of hospital stay, disability, and birth defects. We recorded each study's definition of an SAE if it varied from our definition. Respiratory health‐related quality of life CRQ and SGRQ are widely‐used, reliable and valid measures of patient‐reported health status in COPD (Guyatt 1987; Jones 1992). SGRQ scores three domains of health status (symptoms, patient activity, and disease impact), and reports scores ranging from zero (best) to 100 (worst). The Minimally Clinical Important Difference (MCID) is approximately four (Schunemann 2003). That is, a clinically meaningful change in health status is equal to a change of about four points on SGRQ. CRQ scores four domains (shortness of breath, fatigue, emotional function, and mastery), reports scores ranging from one (worst) to seven (best), and has an MCID of 0.5 (Schunemann 2005). While CRQ and SGRQ provide very similar information and are highly correlated, SGRQ is less responsive; it was shown to underestimate treatment effects when compared to CRQ in identical populations (Puhan 2006). Thus, pooling SGRQ data with CRQ data may spuriously suggest heterogeneity of treatment effect. Therefore, SGRQ and CRQ were considered as separate outcomes; this approach agrees with the recommendations of Puhan 2006, who suggest that mean differences for SGRQ and CRQ should be reported separately. Acute exacerbations of COPD We included AECOPD as a main outcome because exacerbations are consistently linked to mortality, morbidity, and costly hospitalisations. Since a consensus definition and standard reporting criteria do not exist for AECOPD (Cazzola 2008), we performed a meta‐analysis of AECOPD data only when study authors used one of the following definitions: increase in symptoms precipitating the use of antibiotics; increase in symptoms precipitating the use of systemic steroids; increase in symptoms precipitating emergency room visit; or hospitalisation. The MCID for AECOPD outcomes is not established: Calverley 2005 estimated an MCID of 20% to 25% using a crude anchor‐based approach, while Chapman 2013 used an expert consensus process to estimate an MCID of 11%. Secondary outcomes Trough (pre‐dose) Forced Expiratory Volume in One Second (FEV1). Peak (post‐dose) FEV1. Six‐minute walking test (6MWT). Adverse effects. Comments about secondary outcomes Forced expiratory volume FEV1 is the volume of air forcibly exhaled one second after maximum inhalation. FEV1 is often used for staging COPD (GOLD 2017): FEV1 is 20% lower than normal for patients with mild COPD and 70% lower than normal for patients with very severe COPD. FEV1 is also used to assess treatment effect. However, the MCID for FEV1 has not been quantitatively established (expert opinion proposes an MCID of 100 mL to 140 mL) (Cazzola 2008). Moreover, FEV1 is an intermediate endpoint, representing airflow as a surrogate for clinically important outcomes. Surrogate outcomes are not patient‐centred. Nevertheless, we included trough FEV1 because one meta‐analysis points to a modest correlation between increased trough FEV1 and improved SGRQ (Westwood 2011). For the purpose of this review we will consider the MCID for FEV1 to be 100 mL (Donohue 2005). Six‐minute walking test In the ECLIPSE study (a non‐interventional cohort study of treated COPD patients), one‐year change in 6MWT predicted death in the subsequent 12 months. The mean between‐group change between survivors and non‐survivors was 30 metres (95% CI 26 to 34). Using these results, Polkey 2013 proposed an MCID of about 30 metres. Adverse effects We analysed all‐cause adverse effects and serious adverse events reported in studies of LABA or LAMA.</TypesofOutcomeMeasures>
</root>

