<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <Objectives>To compare the efficacy and safety of outpatient versus inpatient treatment in low‐risk patients with acute PE for the outcomes of all‐cause and PE‐related mortality; bleeding; and adverse events such as haemodynamic instability, recurrence of PE and patients' satisfaction.</Objectives>
<TypesofStudies>We included randomised controlled trials (RCTs) and quasi‐RCTs (in which allocation to treatment was obtained by alternation, use of alternate medical records, date of birth or other predictable methods) in this systematic review. We included quasi‐RCTs as we did not anticipate finding many RCTs in this area.</TypesofStudies>
<TypesofParticipants>We included adults (18 years and older) diagnosed with low‐risk acute pulmonary embolism (PE), defined as acute onset of dyspnoea or chest pain together with a new contrast‐filling defect on single‐ or multi‐detector computed tomography (CT) pulmonary angiography or pulmonary digital angiography, a new high‐probability ventilation‐perfusion lung scan or documentation of a new proximal deep vein thrombosis (DVT) either by venous ultrasonography or contrast venography. We considered people to be of low risk if they were classified as low risk by any validated or non‐validated measurement tool that aimed to classify mortality risk rate related to PE, such as the Geneva prediction score (GPS) , the Pulmonary Embolism Severity Index (PESI), the simplified PESI (sPESI) or the Hestia criteria.</TypesofParticipants>
<TypesofInterventions>Intervention group: participants allocated to home (outpatient) management for acute PE. Control group: participants allocated to hospital (inpatient) management for acute PE. We considered outpatients as people who were discharged within 36 hours after the low‐risk acute PE diagnosis and who then completed treatment at home (outpatient care).</TypesofInterventions>
<TypesofOutcomeMeasures>Primary outcomes Short‐term all‐cause mortality (from the date of randomisation to 7 to 10 days). Long‐term all‐cause mortality (from the date of randomisation to 90 days). Long‐term all‐cause mortality at 90 days included any all‐cause mortality noted from the date of randomisation to 90 days. We considered both all‐cause mortality and PE‐related mortality. Secondary outcomes Bleeding (from the date of randomisation to 90 days): we defined major bleeding as fatal or clinically overt bleeding resulting in fall of haemoglobin by 2 g/L or more or bleeding into critical anatomical sites (subdural haematoma, intraspinal haemorrhage, retroperitoneal, intraocular, pericardial, atraumatic intra‐articular) or leading to transfusion of 2 U or more of blood or red cells (Schulman 2005). We defined minor bleeding as bleeding requiring intervention but not qualifying as a major bleeding, including bleeding precipitating treatment cessation (Schulman 2005). Adverse effects, such as haemodynamic instability (from the date of randomisation to 90 days). Recurrence of PE (from the date of randomisation to 90 days). Participant satisfaction or compliance, or both (from the date of randomisation to 90 days): we accepted methods used by study investigators, including Likert scale questionnaires.</TypesofOutcomeMeasures>
</root>

