<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <Objectives>To assess the effectiveness and safety of NIPPV for preventing complications in patients who have undergone pulmonary resection for lung cancer.</Objectives>
<TypesofStudies>We included randomised controlled trials (RCTs) and quasi‐RCTs with no restriction regarding intervention and follow‐up length. We did not include cross‐over trials. We also excluded trials that only compared ventilatory modes of non‐invasive ventilation.</TypesofStudies>
<TypesofParticipants>Patients aged above 18 years of both genders, who underwent any type of lung resection (pneumectomy, lobectomy, segmentectomy) for lung cancer (small‐cell lung carcinoma (SCLC) or non‐small‐cell lung carcinoma (NSCLC)).</TypesofParticipants>
<TypesofInterventions>We included studies in which the intervention was non‐invasive positive pressure ventilation (NIPPV) started in the immediate postoperative period (defined as the first 24 hours after surgery) applied through a nasal or face mask. Two modalities of NIPPV were used: either continuous positive airway pressure (CPAP) or bi‐level positive airway pressure mode. We included studies which used as a control one or a combination of the following interventions: oxygen therapy in order to obtain pulse oximetry oxygen saturation (SpO2) ≥ 92% or arterial partial pressure of oxygen (PaO2) ≥ 65 mmHg; chest physiotherapy techniques for removing secretions; breathing exercises; incentive spirometry; no intervention.</TypesofInterventions>
<TypesofOutcomeMeasures>Primary outcomes Pulmonary complication rate (i.e. pulmonary infections, bronchial congestion, atelectasis, acute lung injury, pleural fistula). Rate of intubation. Mortality. Secondary outcomes Postoperative use of antibiotics. Length of intensive care unit stay. Length of hospital stay. Adverse effects related to NIPPV (i.e. skin damage, pulmonary aspiration, gastric distension, vomiting, asphyxia, pneumothorax, conjunctivitis, sinusitis, mask discomfort, claustrophobia).</TypesofOutcomeMeasures>
</root>

