<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <Objectives>To evaluate the effectiveness of interventions using SNSs to promote the uptake of and adherence to contraception in reproductive‐age women.</Objectives>
<TypesofStudies>We considered interventional studies including randomised controlled trials (RCTs) and non‐randomised interventional studies (NRS) to include non‐RCTs. We expected limited evidence from RCTs that utilised an SNS as an intervention. Thus, we included NRS to examine the evidence base broadly.</TypesofStudies>
<TypesofParticipants>Women of reproductive age who may have initiated contraceptive use, switched to a different method or continued to use the same method. Reproductive age was defined as between 15 and 49 years of age as per the World Health Organization (WHO) definition (WHO 2006). In studies that included both sexes, we requested results pertaining to women from the authors. Postpartum or postabortal women were also included.</TypesofParticipants>
<TypesofInterventions>We included studies where the intervention was delivered either solely via a named SNS, or in conjunction with another method. We included interventions if the purpose was to improve uptake and adherence, or both uptake and adherence to contraception compared to standard delivery of care or another intervention. The included interventions fulfilled one of the following aims: improved uptake of contraception; promoted use of a specific contraceptive method; promoted uptake of more effective contraceptive methods; improved adherence to contraception; and both improved uptake and adherence to contraception. Interventions were included if they targeted current and potential contraception users. The authors definition of more effective contraceptive methods was accepted, although this was likely to include long‐acting reversible contraceptive methods. The interventions had to be delivered through named SNSs where the participant had a personal account that allowed them to access the intervention. Although not an exclusion criteria, SNSs were expected to allow participants to interact with each other. We excluded any intervention delivered by an application or website where a personal account was not required, where the intervention could only be utilised when downloaded, or if participants could not interact with the intervention directly. We included SNSs available in a downloadable form only if they also had an open‐access website.</TypesofInterventions>
<TypesofOutcomeMeasures>Primary outcomes Contraception use (for at least three months postintervention), which included: initiation of a new method; increased uptake of more effective methods; improved adherence to a method; and both increased uptake and improved adherence. Contraception use was be assessed in various ways, and we accepted the method used by the trial investigator. The time frame for assessment was three months or more for the initiation of a new method and improved adherence of an existing method as defined by the study. Secondary outcomes Change in attitude or knowledge about contraception. Attitudes towards the use of SNSs as an intervention.</TypesofOutcomeMeasures>
</root>

