<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <Objectives>To assess the effects of using dental cavity liners in the placement of Class I and Class II resin‐based composite posterior restorations in permanent teeth in children and adults.</Objectives>
<TypesofStudies>All studies included were randomised controlled clinical trials comparing the use of liners under Class I and Class II posterior resin‐based composite restorations in permanent teeth. We included both parallel and split‐mouth designs. We excluded studies examining: bases; amalgam or any other metallic restorations; any indirect restorations; anterior restorations; liners in vitro.</TypesofStudies>
<TypesofParticipants>Adults or children with at least one restoration in a posterior permanent tooth/teeth undergoing a Class I or Class II resin‐based composite restoration(s).</TypesofParticipants>
<TypesofInterventions>Any type of dental cavity liner placed under a Class I or Class II resin‐based composite restoration on a posterior tooth was considered, including but not limited to calcium hydroxide, glass ionomer, resin‐modified glass ionomer, flowable composite, zinc phosphate cement, zinc, and eugenol cement . The comparison group in included trials received Class I or Class II resin‐based composite restoration on a posterior tooth directly bonded to the tooth without the use of a dental cavity liner.</TypesofInterventions>
<TypesofOutcomeMeasures>Primary outcomes Postoperative hypersensitivity to hot, cold, biting, chewing, and/or sweets experienced by the patient within 1 month following the intervention. Postoperative hypersensitivity could be measured by a visual analog scale (VAS) or by hypersensitivity present or absent as tested by dentist or patient self‐report. Restoration failure. Survival time of the resin‐based composite restoration (in months) from the time of placement with a minimum follow‐up of 1 year. Secondary outcomes Cost of materials. Adverse events: pulpal involvement, tooth fracture, hypersensitivity reactions to the materials, etc. or any other adverse event described in any of the studies.</TypesofOutcomeMeasures>
</root>

