<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <Objectives>To assess the benefits and harms of intralesional treatment by curettage compared to wide resection for central low‐grade chondrosarcoma (LGCS) of the long bones.</Objectives>
<TypesofStudies>Since no RCTs or other prospective studies were available, we included retrospective cohort studies comparing oncologic outcome of intralesional treatment of LGCS to wide resection in the long bones (i.e. humerus, radius, ulna, femur, tibia and fibula). In addition, we included case series with at least 20 participants. We also included studies examining other types of chondrosarcoma, from which we retrieved data related to central LGCS. If RCTs become available in literature, they still will be eligible for inclusion in future versions of the review.</TypesofStudies>
<TypesofParticipants>We included all participants with central LGCS in the long bones. We did not apply age restrictions.</TypesofParticipants>
<TypesofInterventions>We compared intralesional treatment (curettage) with or without adjuvant (phenol and ethanol, cryosurgery, bone cement or combinations) to wide resection, including amputation.</TypesofInterventions>
<TypesofOutcomeMeasures>We prespecified the following outcomes, which are also included in the 'Summary of findings' table. Primary outcomes Primary outcome was recurrence‐free survival (defined as local recurrence and/or metastases), with a minimum follow‐up duration of two years after index surgery. Secondary outcomes We considered the following secondary outcomes: incidence of pathological upgrading of tumour; functional outcome based on Musculoskeletal Tumor Society (MSTS) score, if available. The MSTS score is a well‐accepted and commonly used score to determine function after surgery for bone tumours (Enneking 1993). It includes six categories (pain, function, emotional acceptance, use of supports, walking ability and gait), with numerical values from 0 to 5 points; in total 30 points can be reached, often also presented as percentage, with 100% equalling 30 points, and 30 points or 100% indicating no functional limitations; overall rate of major complications based on the following adverse events, if available: fracture, infection, re‐operation (due to reasons other than progression of disease) or thromboembolic events. Grading of adverse events is outside the scope of this review.</TypesofOutcomeMeasures>
</root>

